<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>slimsag</title><link>https://slimsag.com/</link><description>Recent content on slimsag</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://slimsag.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>War with small language models</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/war-with-small-language-models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/war-with-small-language-models/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everyone knows how error-prone, blissfully naive, and illogical &lt;em>large&lt;/em> language models can be a times. And so I have a bit of a self-deprecating joke wherein I say I used a small language model to create something - to write some code, to create a document, etc. i.e. my brain is only slightly more intelligent than a bag of bricks. I both believe this &lt;em>and&lt;/em> am okay with this. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="war-with-small-language-models">War with small language models&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I think what&amp;rsquo;s fascinating is how I can look around myself and see accomplishments of my past self; whether it be the career I&amp;rsquo;ve had, the family I&amp;rsquo;ve rescued, the garden I&amp;rsquo;ve cared for year-over-year, or code I&amp;rsquo;ve written in past years that others seem to appreciate more than I do today (a uniquely fascinating feeling in itself.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being able to introspect on past accomplishments - and more importantly reflect on my state of mind during the time I was making those achievements - tells me that I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved great things through two primary means:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Most often through sheer luck or encountering uniquely impactful individuals through environments I put myself in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By going to war with my small language model, i.e. brain.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In its default state, my small language model would love to sit around, watch mind-numbing YouTube videos, procrastinate, embrace seemingly bi-polar thoughts of anxiety or fear for the future, enjoy the latest hype train or controversial discussion that the tech scene has to offer, neglect chores, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A naive onlooker might be able to observe such a small language model and identify its behavior patterns, where it gets positive and negative feelings, how the context and environment of the day plays into its outputs, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A more intelligent onlooker, however, might be able to observe that although the small language model is.. well, rather naive and frankly stupid - that its training data has something fundamentally strange in it. The daily desires and short-lived ups and downs, which appear frankly erratic, barely influence the long-term desire to so something &lt;em>ultimately great - an achievement like no other&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A drive and almost hard-coded sentiment that underpins everything, enforcing that what the small language model does day to day virtually doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, because there &lt;em>must&lt;/em> exist a singular spectacular achievement within the lifetime or else there was no lifetime to begin with. A theory that the small language model &lt;em>would have no reason to have been created&lt;/em> if it were not for a great achievement towards the end of its function - and so therefor there &lt;em>must exist&lt;/em> a great achievement somewhere in its execution despite any localized challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is only with that sentiment and undertone, that war can exist - that the daily annoyances of the small language models&amp;rsquo; limited context, seemingly swaying daily thoughts of positivity and negativity, can all blur away to instead build towards the the drive and passion for a long-term great achievement - an environment where frankly nothing else matters - neatly encapsulated in that small language model.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thats-all-for-now-folks">That&amp;rsquo;s all for now, folks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The above is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find a way to articulate / express for a while, I hope you enjoyed it or find it useful for your own path in life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RFC8667: Sillycon Valley</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/rfc8667-sillycon-valley/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/rfc8667-sillycon-valley/</guid><description>&lt;p>Proposed variant of / inspired fanatically by &lt;a href="https://www.secrethitler.com">another popular tabletop game&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="game-start">GAME START&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All players are given a random role:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>One player per game: &lt;code>VC&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~40% of players: &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>25% chance one &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code> may be &lt;code>CRYPTO CEO&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>15% chance one &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code> may be &lt;code>LAB CEO&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5% chance one &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code> may be &lt;code>JUICE CEO&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5% chance one &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code> may be &lt;code>UNICORN CEO&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~60% of players: &lt;code>DEV&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All players are assumed to be good open source &lt;code>DEV&lt;/code>s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nobody can see each other’s roles, except &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code>s can see who is &lt;code>VC&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="deck-function">DECK FUNCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>40% probability of drawing &lt;code>GROWTH&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>60% probability of drawing &lt;code>FOSS&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="turns">TURNS&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In rotating order, each player will be &amp;rsquo;the &lt;code>1xDEV&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo; and gets to submit a &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> to Hacky News&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All &lt;code>DEV&lt;/code>s must upvote/downvote the Hacky News submission and decide whether they want to depend on the &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code>s work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the submission doesn’t reach the front page (no majority vote), there is no &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> so &lt;code>goto next_turn;&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the submission would reach the front page, but the &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> is secretly &lt;code>VC&lt;/code>, the &lt;code>VC&lt;/code> shouts &lt;code>IPO!&lt;/code> and wins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the submission reaches the front page, a &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> has been nominated:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If the &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> is secretly..
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>VC&lt;/code> or &lt;code>UNICORN CEO&lt;/code>, they can shout &lt;code>IPO!&lt;/code> and the &lt;code>VC&lt;/code> and &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code> win&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>CRYPTO CEO&lt;/code>, they can invoke &lt;code>CRYPTO!&lt;/code>, flip a coin, if heads they steal all &lt;code>VC&lt;/code> funds and win game for themselves. Tails they go to jail (out of the game entirely.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>LAB CEO&lt;/code>, they can invoke &lt;code>FAKE IT TILL YOU MAKE IT!&lt;/code>, flip a coin, if heads they steal all &lt;code>VC&lt;/code> funds and win game for themselves. Tails they go to jail (out of the game entirely.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>JUICE CEO&lt;/code>, they can invoke &lt;code>SQUEEZED TO DEATH&lt;/code>, two coin flips, if both heads they can shout &lt;code>IPO!&lt;/code> and &lt;code>VC&lt;/code> and &lt;code>CEO&lt;/code> win, otherwise CEO out of the game entirely.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> is actually just a normal open source &lt;code>DEV&lt;/code>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> draws 3 random cards, reviews and discards 1, giving the remaining 2 to the &lt;code>1xDEV&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;code>1xDEV&lt;/code> is given 2 cards by the &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code>, must discard 1, must play/put-down the other&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="playing-cards">PLAYING CARDS&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If five &lt;code>GROWTH&lt;/code> cards are played, the &lt;code>VC&lt;/code> shouts &lt;code>IPO!&lt;/code> and wins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If five &lt;code>FOSS&lt;/code> cards are played, the &lt;code>DEV&lt;/code>s win&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the 3rd and 4th &lt;code>GROWTH&lt;/code> cards are played, the current &lt;code>10xDEV&lt;/code> chooses one player to suffer &lt;code>BURNOUT&lt;/code> - that player can no longer do anything but talk.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Slack to destroy >90d history of free communities</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/slack-to-destroy-history-of-free-communities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/slack-to-destroy-history-of-free-communities/</guid><description>&lt;p>Slack today sent an announcement email indicating they will delete free workspace content older than a year, and that &amp;ldquo;Free workspaces will continue to have full access to the past 90 days of message history and file storage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just another reason to always be a step ahead and anticipate startups and companies like Slack, GitHub, and Discord will eventually enshittify your usage of their products. Hopefully one day FOSS can actually compete with these services&amp;rsquo; UX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The full announcement email can be viewed below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/slack.jpg">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/slack.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The most ridiculous cat photos ever</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/meowarmy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/meowarmy/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is literally just to tell you I put ridiculous cat photos at &lt;a href="https://meow.army">https://meow.army&lt;/a> - enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking &amp;lsquo;how good can cat photos be?&amp;rsquo; - well here are two samples for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/cat1.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/cat2.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>onlybits.org: a place to show off your hot FOSS bits</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/onlybits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/onlybits/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the story of how some lady using a variation of my username led to me creating a website for FOSS software developers to compete with an $18b company.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-it-began">How it began&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I use a website called &lt;a href="https://f5bot.com">f5bot&lt;/a> to get alerts about my username &lt;code>slimsag&lt;/code> on the internet, so that when people mention me or my work on Reddit, Hacker news, etc. I get an email letting me know. It&amp;rsquo;s been useful to see people asking questions or discussing my open source projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/f5bot.jpg">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/f5bot.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the same time, I tend ot advertise my &lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/slimsag">GitHub sponsors page&lt;/a> somewhat regularly. I try not to be overbearing about it, but also just let people know: you can sponsor my FOSS work if you want to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="then-the-spam-began">Then the spam began&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Some lady adopted a variation of my username &lt;code>slimsag&lt;/code> as her own Reddit username, which caused f5bot to pick up on it (it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do whole-word matches, but rather substring) - my inbox was getting notifications every day about this lady advertising her OF profile:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlyfans-spam.jpg">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlyfans-spam.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first I was a bit put-off by these notifications: I don&amp;rsquo;t want this crap in my inbox every morning. But over time, I came to realize how much she is advertising &lt;em>her work and soliciting donations&lt;/em>.. and I am not.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="announcing-onlybits">Announcing OnlyBits&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s time for FOSS developers to stop living in the shadows! For too long people have been afraid to share that they too write nasty FOSS code on the side for strangers&amp;rsquo; pleasure on the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another popular website&amp;rsquo;s creators make $4.46 billion USD per year, but how much do FOSS developers make per year?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>onlybits.org aims to get FOSS developers a fraction of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use-it">How to use it&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Registration is simple - you&amp;rsquo;re already registered. &lt;code>https://onlybits.org/username&lt;/code> redirects to &lt;code>https://github.com/username&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example: you can view some hot, steamy bits at &lt;a href="https://onlybits.org/hexops/mach">onlybits.org/hexops/mach&lt;/a> - but don&amp;rsquo;t forget to tip at &lt;a href="https://onlybits.org/sponsors/slimsag">onlybits.org/sponsors/slimsag&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To advertise, you can also use the &lt;code>OB&lt;/code> logo and emojis - like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlybits.png">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlybits.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>