<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on slimsag</title><link>https://slimsag.com/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on slimsag</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://slimsag.com/categories/tech/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slack to destroy >90d history of free communities</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/slack-to-destroy-history-of-free-communities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/slack-to-destroy-history-of-free-communities/</guid><description>&lt;p>Slack today sent an announcement email indicating they will delete free workspace content older than a year, and that &amp;ldquo;Free workspaces will continue to have full access to the past 90 days of message history and file storage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just another reason to always be a step ahead and anticipate startups and companies like Slack, GitHub, and Discord will eventually enshittify your usage of their products. Hopefully one day FOSS can actually compete with these services&amp;rsquo; UX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The full announcement email can be viewed below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/slack.jpg">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/slack.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>onlybits.org: a place to show off your hot FOSS bits</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/onlybits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/onlybits/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the story of how some lady using a variation of my username led to me creating a website for FOSS software developers to compete with an $18b company.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-it-began">How it began&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I use a website called &lt;a href="https://f5bot.com">f5bot&lt;/a> to get alerts about my username &lt;code>slimsag&lt;/code> on the internet, so that when people mention me or my work on Reddit, Hacker news, etc. I get an email letting me know. It&amp;rsquo;s been useful to see people asking questions or discussing my open source projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/f5bot.jpg">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/f5bot.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the same time, I tend ot advertise my &lt;a href="https://github.com/sponsors/slimsag">GitHub sponsors page&lt;/a> somewhat regularly. I try not to be overbearing about it, but also just let people know: you can sponsor my FOSS work if you want to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="then-the-spam-began">Then the spam began&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Some lady adopted a variation of my username &lt;code>slimsag&lt;/code> as her own Reddit username, which caused f5bot to pick up on it (it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do whole-word matches, but rather substring) - my inbox was getting notifications every day about this lady advertising her OF profile:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlyfans-spam.jpg">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlyfans-spam.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first I was a bit put-off by these notifications: I don&amp;rsquo;t want this crap in my inbox every morning. But over time, I came to realize how much she is advertising &lt;em>her work and soliciting donations&lt;/em>.. and I am not.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="announcing-onlybits">Announcing OnlyBits&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s time for FOSS developers to stop living in the shadows! For too long people have been afraid to share that they too write nasty FOSS code on the side for strangers&amp;rsquo; pleasure on the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another popular website&amp;rsquo;s creators make $4.46 billion USD per year, but how much do FOSS developers make per year?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>onlybits.org aims to get FOSS developers a fraction of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use-it">How to use it&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Registration is simple - you&amp;rsquo;re already registered. &lt;code>https://onlybits.org/username&lt;/code> redirects to &lt;code>https://github.com/username&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example: you can view some hot, steamy bits at &lt;a href="https://onlybits.org/hexops/mach">onlybits.org/hexops/mach&lt;/a> - but don&amp;rsquo;t forget to tip at &lt;a href="https://onlybits.org/sponsors/slimsag">onlybits.org/sponsors/slimsag&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To advertise, you can also use the &lt;code>OB&lt;/code> logo and emojis - like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlybits.png">&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/onlybits.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>