<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>life on slimsag</title><link>https://slimsag.com/categories/life/</link><description>Recent content in life on slimsag</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://slimsag.com/categories/life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>War with small language models</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/war-with-small-language-models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/war-with-small-language-models/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everyone knows how error-prone, blissfully naive, and illogical &lt;em>large&lt;/em> language models can be a times. And so I have a bit of a self-deprecating joke wherein I say I used a small language model to create something - to write some code, to create a document, etc. i.e. my brain is only slightly more intelligent than a bag of bricks. I both believe this &lt;em>and&lt;/em> am okay with this. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="war-with-small-language-models">War with small language models&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I think what&amp;rsquo;s fascinating is how I can look around myself and see accomplishments of my past self; whether it be the career I&amp;rsquo;ve had, the family I&amp;rsquo;ve rescued, the garden I&amp;rsquo;ve cared for year-over-year, or code I&amp;rsquo;ve written in past years that others seem to appreciate more than I do today (a uniquely fascinating feeling in itself.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being able to introspect on past accomplishments - and more importantly reflect on my state of mind during the time I was making those achievements - tells me that I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved great things through two primary means:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Most often through sheer luck or encountering uniquely impactful individuals through environments I put myself in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By going to war with my small language model, i.e. brain.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In its default state, my small language model would love to sit around, watch mind-numbing YouTube videos, procrastinate, embrace seemingly bi-polar thoughts of anxiety or fear for the future, enjoy the latest hype train or controversial discussion that the tech scene has to offer, neglect chores, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A naive onlooker might be able to observe such a small language model and identify its behavior patterns, where it gets positive and negative feelings, how the context and environment of the day plays into its outputs, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A more intelligent onlooker, however, might be able to observe that although the small language model is.. well, rather naive and frankly stupid - that its training data has something fundamentally strange in it. The daily desires and short-lived ups and downs, which appear frankly erratic, barely influence the long-term desire to so something &lt;em>ultimately great - an achievement like no other&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A drive and almost hard-coded sentiment that underpins everything, enforcing that what the small language model does day to day virtually doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, because there &lt;em>must&lt;/em> exist a singular spectacular achievement within the lifetime or else there was no lifetime to begin with. A theory that the small language model &lt;em>would have no reason to have been created&lt;/em> if it were not for a great achievement towards the end of its function - and so therefor there &lt;em>must exist&lt;/em> a great achievement somewhere in its execution despite any localized challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is only with that sentiment and undertone, that war can exist - that the daily annoyances of the small language models&amp;rsquo; limited context, seemingly swaying daily thoughts of positivity and negativity, can all blur away to instead build towards the the drive and passion for a long-term great achievement - an environment where frankly nothing else matters - neatly encapsulated in that small language model.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thats-all-for-now-folks">That&amp;rsquo;s all for now, folks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The above is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find a way to articulate / express for a while, I hope you enjoyed it or find it useful for your own path in life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The most ridiculous cat photos ever</title><link>https://slimsag.com/2024/meowarmy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slimsag.com/2024/meowarmy/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is literally just to tell you I put ridiculous cat photos at &lt;a href="https://meow.army">https://meow.army&lt;/a> - enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking &amp;lsquo;how good can cat photos be?&amp;rsquo; - well here are two samples for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/cat1.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://slimsag.com/img/2024/cat2.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>